pictage.com 2013-04-11

# Pictage Privacy Policy

#### What personal information does Pictage collect and how do we use it?

The personal information we collect consists of data that you have given during the registration process. We require that all guests who would like to place an order provide us with their name, address, zip code, e-mail address and credit card information.We also keep track of your visits to the site and all purchases you make through us with this information.

####  Does Pictage disclose my personally identifiable information to others? If so, to whom?

Your contact and order information is passed onto the partner photographer or vendors who are responsible for fulfilling photo orders to your event. If you are an event holder, Pictage reserves the right to contact you about your account. From time-to-time, we might establish a business relationship with other persons or entities whom we believe trustworthy and whom we have asked to confirm that their Privacy Policies are consistent with ours. Some information, including photographer client data (i.e., bride and groom information) is used directly by our partners.

Information we collect is owned strictly by Pictage (unless it originates from a partner's site) and is used to enhance your experience on our site, to show you Pictage-related content and to display the content according to your studio preferences. We also use such personal information to send you information and promotional materials regarding Pictage and some of our partners. Your contact information may be used if it becomes necessary to contact you. We may also disclose your personal information when we believe the law requires it.

In order to protect the privacy of our event holders, your e-mail address is made available to the registered owner of any event that you attempt to log in to while logged onto Pictage.

You have two "Opt-Out" choices that you may manage once logged into the Pictage web site. First, you may opt to discontinue receiving valuable offers from Pictage. Second, you may opt out of receiving valuable offers from our partner photographers and other merchants. If you choose to opt out, you will not receive any e-mail discounts or any other form of direct mail from our partners or us. Changes to your status are made through the "my profile" link in the upper right corner of your homepage at [www.pictage.com](http://www.pictage.com/).

Our site may contain links to other sites. If you jump to these other sites, Pictage will not forward any information it has received from you to the next site. However, Pictage is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other web sites. Although this Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices or policies of partners, we require that all of our partners agree not to use your personal information, except as fully disclosed to you or authorized by you.

####  How does Pictage store my personal identifiable information?

Pictage also keeps your IP address confidential and uses it to help diagnose problems with our server, analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.  
Pictage uses a firewall and password protected accounts to prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. All machines are in a secured environment. Any archived information is also kept in a secured location.

#### How is my credit card information protected?

We do not store any credit card information at Pictage. We have partnered with VeriSign, for our e-commerce capabilities.

VeriSign's (Nasdaq:VRSN) critical infrastructure services deliver an unmatched level of security and reliability to Internet and telecommunications customers around the world. Nearly all of the Fortune 500 companies, governmental bodies and other organizations, hundreds of thousands of small businesses and hundreds of service providers rely on VeriSign to engage in digital commerce and communications.

#### What is a "cookie"? Does Pictage use them?

Yes, cookies are an integral part of efficiently and easily storing and retrieving information

A cookie is information that Pictage puts on your hard disk so that it can remember something about you at a later time. Typically, a cookie records your preferences when using a particular site. Using the web's Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP), each request for a web page is independent of all other requests. For this reason, the web page server has no memory of what pages it has sent to a user previously, or anything about your previous visits. A cookie is a mechanism that allows Pictage's server to store its own information about a user on the user's own computer. You can view the cookies that have been stored on your hard disk (although the content stored in each cookie may not make much sense to you). The location of the cookies depends on the browser. Internet Explorer stores each cookie as a separate file under a Windows subdirectory. Netscape stores all cookies in a single cookies.txt file. Opera stores them in a single cookies.dat file.

Cookies are commonly used to rotate the banner ads that a site sends, so that it doesn't keep sending the same ad as it sends you a succession of requested pages. They can also be used to customize pages for you based on your browser type or other information you may have provided us. Web users must agree to let cookies be saved for them, but, in general, it helps Pictage to serve users better. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user may be limited in some areas of our site. For example, the user may not be able to participate in any of our sweepstakes, contests or monthly drawings that take place. Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

#### Can I delete personally identifiable information on the site?

Yes, you can. If you no longer want Pictage or its partners to communicate with you, edit your profile through the "My Profile" link in the upper right corner of your homepage at [www.pictage.com](http://www.pictage.com/). As an alternative, when you are at the log-in page, you can click on the "click here if this isn't you" button and that will erase any stored cookies.

#### Why did you receive an e-mail from us?

You will receive an e-mail from Pictage if, (a) your e-mail address is either listed with us as someone who has willingly shared this address for the purpose of receiving information in the future ("opt-in"), or (b) you have registered or purchased, or otherwise have an existing relationship with us. 

#### How can you stop receiving e-mail from us?

Each e-mail sent contains an easy, automated way for you to cease receiving e-mail from Pictage. If you wish to do this, simply follow the instructions at the end of any e-mail. Please note that requests to be removed from an e-mail distribution list can take up to 7 business days.

If you have received unwanted, unsolicited e-mail sent via this system or purporting to be sent via this system, please forward a copy of that e-mail with your comments to [help@pictage.com](mailto:help@pictage.com) for review. We respect your time and attention by monitoring the frequency of our mailings.

#### Are my pictures available for public viewing?

After you view the proofs your photographer has taken for you, you can edit these photos for viewing by your invited guests. Your site is password protected and only those people that you give the password to will have access to your event photos.

#### What do you do with survey responses?

From time-to-time, our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level).

Surveys are normally conducted through SurveyMonkey.com. This is a password protected web site that provides businesses with the software to develop, disseminate, record and analyze survey responses. Your responses are completely confidential and are used to help us tailor our services to you. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. We appreciate your participation in the on-going development of our service.

#### Referral Promotional Programs

If a user elects to participate in any of our promotional referral programs for directing guests to our site, we will ask them for the friend's name and email address. Pictage will automatically send the friend an e-mail inviting them to visit the site. Pictage stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this e-mail. The guest may contact Pictage at [remove@pictage.com](mailto:remove@pictage.com) to request the removal of this information from our database.

#### Changes to privacy policy

Pictage reserves the right from time to time to make changes to its Privacy Policy.

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on our homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an e-mail, if you have "opted-in" to receive e-mail notifications. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us, or you may write to us at: Pictage Inc., 1580 Francisco St, Torrance, CA 90501 (Ph: 1-877-PICTAGE).

Top of Page
